Luffy and Robin needed to recover, so the Going Merry remained anchored off the uninhabited island for four days.
من أجل حصول لوفي وروبين على بعض الرّاحة، رست الغوينغ ميري
After that, we set sail, and now this is the third morning since we resumed our voyage.
بعد ذلك، أبحرنا
Today's weather is a gorgeous mix of spring...
...إنّه يوم جميل، الرّبيع جزئي
and occasional bouts of summer.
مع نوبات صيفيّة من حين لآخر
What a beautiful day!
يا له من يومٍ جميل
Nami my sweet!
نامي-سان
I made pomme paille. Mademoiselle, if you would...
...أعددتُ باي البطاطا يا آنستي، تفضّلي
Mmm, it's delicious!
إنّها لذيذة
I'm overjoyed!
أنا سعيد
Keep it down! I'm trying to sleep!
اخرس أيّها النّذل، إنّك تُقلق نومي
Yeah, yeah... Sorry about that, cactus head.
أجل، أجل، متأسّفين على ذلك يا رأس الصّبّار
What'd you say, dartboard brows?!
ماذا قلت يا وجه لوحة السِّهام؟
Dar– Did I hear you right, you bastard?!
لوحـ... ماذا قلت أيّها الوغد؟
Dartboard brows.
حواجب السّهام
Luffy! Yeah! Luffy! All right!
لوفي، أجل، لوفي، مرحى
Luffy! Yeah! Luffy!
لوفي، أجل، لوفي
Finally!
أخيرًا
Luffy!
لوفي
This is my frozen-self reenactment.
أنا أقلّد نفسي المجمّدة
The heck...? I can't believe he's doing that after he got frozen and almost died.
يا إلهي... لا أصدّق أنّه يفعل ذلك بعد أن جُمّد وكان على شفا حفرة من الموت
Was it close?
هل قمتُ بعمل جيّد؟
You nailed it! That was exactly it, Luffy!
فعلت، بدوت كذلك تمامًا يا لوفي
Clean that up good, okay, Luffy?!
نظّف ذلك جيّدًا، مفهوم يا لوفي؟
Hm...? Oh! What're you eating, Nami?
ماذا؟ ماذا تأكلين يا نامي؟
It's paille, a potato dish.
إنّه طبق باي البطاطا
Potato, huh? I'm hungry too. Hey, Sanji!
بطاطا؟ أنا جائع أيضًا يا سانجي
Just how much sleep do you need anyway?!
كم تحتاج من النّوم لترضى؟
How much sleep I "need" is my business! Let's settle this!
ذلك يخصّني أنا، سأواجهك إن كنت تريد القتال
They said this is called paille. It's good!
يقال أنّه يدعى باي، إنّه لذيذ
What's paille?
ما معنى باي؟
It's the tail meat of a huge monster named Paille.
إنّه لحم ذيل وحش ضخم يدعى باي
I slew it, though. It was at least a hundred meters tall.
لقد قتلته، كان طوله 100 متر على الأقل
A hundred meters?! That's amazing, Usopp!
مئة متر؟ هذا مذهل يا أوسوبّ
Yeah, and I did it all before breakfast.
كان ذلك سهلًا، قضيتُ عليه قبل الإفطار
What? You got up early and killed it?
ماذا؟ استيقظتَ باكرًا وقتلته؟
Chopper, say my name.
تشوبّر، ردّد اسمي
What? That's, of course, C-Captain...
...ماذا؟ ذلك... بالطّبع يا قـ-قبطان
That's right! My name is Captain... Usopp–
صحيح، هذا هو اسمي... القبطان... أوسوبّ
Robin!
روبين
Hey! Robin my love!
مرحى، روبين-تشان
How are you feeling? Are you chilly?
كيف حالك؟ هل تشعرين بالبرد؟
I'm feeling a lot better all thanks to an amazing doctor.
،أنا أشعر بتحسّن كبير شكرًا لك يا طبيبي الممتاز
Oh, being called an amazing doctor won't make me feel happy or anything, you jerk.
دعوتي بالطّبيب الممتاز لن يجعلني سعيدًا أيّتها الغبيّة
He sure does look happy.
يبدو سعيدًا بالفعل
Yeah.
نعم
Take it easy, Robin.
هوّني على نفسك يا روبين
Don't feel pressured just because Luffy is up and about after experiencing the same thing.
قد تنزعجين عندما ترين لوفي بأفضل حال
It's okay to take your time and rest.
لكن بإمكانك أخذ وقتك والاستراحة
– Yay! – That wasn't a compliement!
مرحى - لم يكن إطراءً -
Robin! Shall I make something to warm you up?
روبين-تشان، هل أعدّ لك شيئًا يُدفئ جسدك؟
How's your appetite?
هل شهيّتك مفتوحة؟
Well...
إذًا... هلّي بكوب من القهوة؟
Absolutely! It'll be my pleasure!
حاضر، بكلّ سرور
What's that?
ما ذلك؟
Anyway, this paille thing is so good that we can't stop eating it.
على أيّ حال، هذا الشّيء الّذي يدعى باي لذيذ جدًّا ولا نستطيع مقاومته، صحيح؟
Yeah, it's yummy!
نعم، إنّه لذيذ
How much would we make if we sold this?
بالمناسبة، ألا تظنّان أنّنا نستطيع درّ بعض المال إن بعنا هذا؟
Hey, Luffy!
يا لوفي
A f-f-frog is doing the front crawl!
ثمّة ضـ-ضفدع يقوم بالسّباحة الحرّة
It went to your side, so take a look!
سبح إلى جهتكم، لذا ألقوا نظرة
Is that true?
أهذا صحيح؟
A frog...? Could it be that frog?
ضفدع... أيعقل أن يكون ذلك الضّفدع؟
Hey, Luffy, are you seriously taking stock in what that dumb admiral said?
يا لوفي، هل تأخذ ما قاله ذلك الأميرال الغبيّ محمل الجدّ؟
For starters, a frog could never do the–
أساسًا، يستحيل أن يقوم ضفدع بالسّباحة الحـ... بلى
It's doing it! A-A frog is doing the front crawl!
إنه كذلك
Let's follow it, guys!
سنتبعه
– Aye!
أجل
Furl the sail! Stand by the oars! Turn the ship to two o'clock!
،افردوا الأشرعة وخذوا المجاديف أديروا السّفينة باتّجاه السّاعة الثّانية
– Aye!
حاضر - بسرعة -
I can't explain it, but I can't fight the urge to go after it!
لا أدري لماذا، لكن أشعر أنّنا يجب أن نلاحقه
Sorry to keep you waiting, mademoiselles.
آسف على التّأخّر يا آنستاي
What the...?
...ما الّذي
What?! What happened?!
ماذا؟ ما الّذي حدث؟
It feels like the ship changed course.
يبدو أنّ السّفينة غيّرت مسارها
Hey, you guys! Who said you could change course without consulting me?!
أنتم، لماذا غيّرتم المسار دون استشارتي؟
Hey, Nami, you've got to hear this!
عليك سماع هذا يا نامي
We found a huge frog with scars all over its body!
وجدنا ضفدعًا ضخمًا مكلّلًا بالنّدوب
The plan's to roast it whole and eat it!
سنحمّصه كلّه ونأكله بكلّ تأكيد
– You're gonna eat it?!
ستأكله؟
Hey, you're right.
...كلامك صحيح
Hm? Is that a lighthouse?
ماذا؟ أتلك منارة؟
Why is there a lighthouse all the way out here? I wonder if someone's there...
ما الّذي تفعله منارة في مكان كذاك؟ ...أتساءل إن كان أحدهم هناك
Wh-What do you see? Is it an island?
مـ-ما الأمر؟ هل ترين جزيرة؟
No, it's a lighthouse. Log poses shouldn't point to places like these.
كلّا، هنالك منارة، ما كانت البوصلة المسجّلة لتشير إلى مكان كذاك
And the frog? Tell us the direction the frog went!
ماذا عن الضّفدع؟ أخبرينا بالاتّجاه الّذي سبح إليه الضّفدع
Not a chance!
إطلاقًا
The frog is headed to the lighthouse.
الضفدع متّجه إلى المنارة
and then dredge them in flour and fry them crisp.
ثمّ نضع عليها الدّقيق ونقليها حتّى تتقرمش
Hey, Sanji!
مهلًا يا سانجي-كن
If our captain says we're going, what choice do we have but to go?
إن قرّر قبطاننا أن نذهب، هل نملك خيارًا آخر؟
Robin...
...روبين
All right! Full speed ahead!
حسنًا، إلى الأمام بأقصى سرعة
– Aye!
أجل
What's with the solidarity?!
ما هذا التّآلف فجأةً؟
– Heave-ho! Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
هيّا بنا، هيّا بنا، هيّا بنا
It's flying!
لقد حلّق
Don't let it get away! Move ahead of it and block its course!
لا تدعوه يهرب، سنسبقه ثمّ نعترض طريقه
– Heave-ho! Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
هيّا بنا، هيّا بنا، هيّا بنا
We ran aground on something!
اصطدمنا باليابسة أو ما شابه
Ah, Nami, Robin, are you two okay?
نامي-سان، روبين-تشان، هل أنتما بخير؟
Yeah, somehow...
...نعم، بطريقةٍ ما
I'm okay.
أنا بخير
Thank goodness.
...جيّد
What? What's that sound?
ماذا؟ ما هذا الصوت؟
What? What's going on?
ماذا؟ ما الّذي يجري؟
Is this...? Don't tell me...
...أهذا...؟ لا يعقل
Why...? In a place like this...?!
لماذا... في مكان كهذا...؟
Ow, ow, ow!
...هذا مؤلم، مؤلم، مؤلم
Go back! Go back! Rotate 180 degrees!
عودوا، عودوا، أديروا السّفينة 180 درجة
What the hell is this?!
ما ذلك بالضبط؟
Wh-Wh-What in the world is this hulking piece of iron?!
مـ-ما هذه الكتلة الحديديّة؟
A ship?
سفينة؟
Impossible! Something shaped like this isn't seaworthy!
كلّا، لا يمكن لشيءٍ بهذا الشّكل أن يسافر على البحر
Hey, frog! Run! What're you doing?!
أيّها الضّفدع اهرب، ما الّذي تفعله؟
Ah! It got run over!
مصيبة، لقد اصطدم به
The ship was puffing out smoke!
كانت السّفينة تنفث الدّخان
Pirates...?
قراصنة...؟
Grandma! Grandma! Pirates are here!
جدّتي، جدّتي، أتى قراصنة
What?! Is that so, Chimney?!
ماذا؟ أهذا صحيح يا تشيمني؟
Okay then, bring the transponder snail to me!
حسنًا إذًا، أحضري لي حلزون الاتّصال
Okay!
حسنًا
This is a problem. Someone came out of the building.
هذه مشكلة، خرجت امرأة من المبنى
They're gonna call for help.
وستستدعي المساعدة
Here it is, Grandma!
تفضّلي يا جدّتي
Um... Hello?
مرحبًا؟
Let's see... What was it? I forgot.
لنرَ... ماذا كنت سأقول؟ نسيت
She's wasted?!
إنّها ثملة إذًا؟
Oh? Paille, huh? It goes good with booze.
ماذا؟ باي؟ يتماشى مذاقه جيّدًا مع الكحول
Whoa! This is tasty!
مذهل، إنّه لذيذ
I'm Chimney. This is our cat, Gonbe,
...أنا تشيمني وهذا قطّنا غونبي
and Grandma Kokoro.
وجدّتي كوكورو
You guys aren't train robbers, are you?
لستم لصوص القطار، أليس كذلك؟
I'm Luffy. I'm the man who'll be King of the Pirates.
أنا لوفي، أنا الرّجل الّذي سيصير ملك القراصنة
Really?!
حقًّا؟ - نعم -
What a funny guy.
يا له من شخصٍ طريف
Say, Chimney, that thing is a steamship, right?
أخبريني يا تشيمني، ذلك الشّيء باخرة، صحيح؟
But with a shape like that, there's no way it could ever sail.
لكن لا يفترض أن تستطيع التّرحال مع شكلٍ كذاك
Never seen nothin' like it, huh?
لم تروا شيئًا كذلك من قبل، أليس كذلك؟
This is the only place in the world it exists.
حتّى إن بحثتم في العالم بأكمله لن تجدوه إلّا في هذا المكان
It's a sea train called the Puffing Tom.
"إنّه قطار بحري يُدعى "توم النّافث
Puffing Tom?
توم النّافث؟
A steam engine turns the paddle wheels as it rides the sea railway.
يدير محرّكٌ بخاريٌّ عجلاتِ التّدوير ويسير على السكّة الحديديّة البحريّة
Railway?
سكّة حديديّة؟
That's right. It floats just below the water's surface.
نعم، إنّها ممتدّة تحت سطح البحر قليلًا
The train travels the same route every day, taking passengers from one island to another.
يرتحل القطار من خلال نفس الطريق كلّ يوم
It also hauls ships and delivers mail.
كما أنّه يحمل السّفن والبريد
She's right. There really is a railway.
معها حقّ، ثمّة سكّة حديديّة فعلًا
Yup! There's both a signal and a partition.
هذا صحيح، ثمّة إشارة وحاجز
It's dangerous to cross the barrier!
من الخطير دخولها هكذا
Dangerous or not, that guy wouldn't understand, right?
حتّى إن كان خطيرًا، ما كان ذلك الشخص ليعرف، صحيح؟
It wasn't nice to send him flying. We were chasing him, you know.
لم يكن من الجميل دهسه فقد كنّا نلاحقه
By "that guy," do you mean Yokozuna?
ماذا؟ أتقصد بـ"ذلك الشّخص" يوكوزونا؟
Yep, that front-crawl frog.
نعم، ضفدع السّباحة الحرّة ذاك
Yokozuna wouldn't die from that.
ما كان يوكوزونا ليموت إثر ذلك
He's the source of all our headaches here at Shift Station.
إنّه أصل كلّ مشكلاتنا في محطّة التّحويل هذه
He loves testing his strength by trying to defeat the sea train.
يهوى تحدّيات القوّة ودائمًا ما يحاول هزيمة القطار البحري
He'll be back.
سيأتي ثانيةً
Testing his strength? Oh! That's why he stood his ground, huh?
تحدّيات القوّة؟ فهمت... لهذا لم يبتعد إذًا؟
He's sure got guts.
إنّه جريء بحقّ
Give me a break! He's a royal pain!
إليك عنّي، لدينا مشكلات
The grill also keeps getting broken!
كُسر حامي السّكّة العديد من المرّات أيضًا
Every time he shows up, the passengers freak out!
إنّه يتسبّب بالمشكلات للرّكّاب في كلّ مرّة يظهر
So that's what he's doing...
...فهمت
Okay, then! I won't eat him!
حسنًا إذًا، لن آكله
I can't eat a fighter!
لن آكل مقاتلًا
Wanting to eat him was your first mistake!
ما كان يجب أن تفكّر في أكل ضفدع من الأساس
So, you guys headed somewhere?
إلى أين تودّون الذّهاب إذًا؟
If you're gonna take the sea train from here, there's:
...إن كنتم ستستقلّون القطار البحري من هنا
St. Poplar, Town of the Spring Queen... Pucci, the Gourmet Town...
...بلدة ملكة الرّبيع، القدّيس بوبلار ...بلدة الذّوّاقة، بوتشي
and San Faldo, the Carnival Town!
...وبلدة الكرنفال، سان فالدو كلّها أماكن ممتعة
If you work for the government, you'd take a separate, special train.
وإن كنتم تعملون مع الحكومة فهنالك قطار خاص ومنفصل
Okay, we'll pick the Gourmet Town.
سنختار بلدة الذّوّاقة إذًا
No, we won't!
بالطّبع لا
Since we've got our own ship, we won't need the train.
بما أنّنا نملك سفينتنا، لن نستقلّ القطار
We can follow our log.
سنتبع البوصلة فحسب
Oh? Where's it pointing?
ماذا؟ إلى أين تشير؟
Due east from here.
شرقًا من هنا
So I see... That would be none other than Water Seven.
فهمت، لا بدّ أنّها تشير لووتر سيفن إذًا
The train you saw earlier came from that island's Blue Station.
القطار الّذي رأيتموه سابقًا أتى من المحطّة الزرقاء لتلك الجزيرة
It's called the City of Water. It's a real nice place.
تُدعى بـ"مدينة الماء". وهي مكان جميل
What's more, the city is known far and wide for its shipbuilding industry.
قبل كلّ شيء، إنّها مدينة صنعت لنفسها اسمًا من خلال السفانة
Their tech is the best in the world!
تقنيّتهم هي الأولى في العالم
Even the World Government favors the ships built there! Amazing, right?
والسّفن الّتي يبنونها تحظى بتفضيل حكومة العالم، أليس ذلك رائعًا؟
Then... they've got some awesome shipwrights, right?!
فهمت... لا بدّ أنّ فيها بعض السفانين مذهلين إذًا، صحيح؟
Not just "some"! Only the world's best shipwrights hang out there!
ليس "البعض" فحسب، بل هي منتدى لأفضل السفانين في العالم
Usopp!
أوسوبّ
Yeah!
أجل
Alright! I've decided!
حسنًا، قُضي الأمر
We'll go and get a shipwright to join us for sure!
سنذهب إلى هناك ونضمّ سفّانًا إلى طاقمنا بالتّأكيد
Oh, is that right? Then hold on a sec.
هكذا إذًا؟ أمهلني لحظة إذًا
Up I go!
ها أنا ذي
What's she up to?
ما الأمر؟
Beats me.
لا أدري
Well, then... Here's a basic map of the island and a letter of introduction.
حسنًا... هذه خريطة بسيطة للجزيرة ورسالة مرجعيّة
Hand this to a guy named Iceburg and ask him to fix up your ship real good.
أعطوا هذه لشخص يدعى أيسبرغ واطلبوا منه أن يصلح سفينتكم على أتمّ وجه
Water Seven is a big place. Don't get lost.
ووتر سيفن مكان كبير، لا تتوهوا
You have a heart of gold, Miss Kokoro! You're so kind!
!كوكورو-سان، لديك قلب كبير !يا لك من شخص لطيف
In a bit, we're gonna go back to Water Seven too.
سوف نعود إلى ووتر سيفن قريبًا أيضًا
Oh, true! If we meet again, first round's on me at my favorite bar.
نعم، إن التقينا ثانيةً، سأدعوكم للشّراب في حانتي المفضّلة
Okay! I hope we see you guys again!
حسنًا، آمل أن نلتقي بكما ثانيةً
At Water Seven, it'll take about a week for the log to register, so kick back and relax.
سيستغرق تسجيل البوصلة نحو أسبوع في ووتر سيفن فلا داعي للعجلة
Yeah! Thanks!
أجل، شكرًا
All right, guys! Get ready to set sail!
حسنًا يا رفاق، استعدّوا للإبحار
– Yeah!
أجل - حسنًا، لنذهب -
Thanks for all your help, Miss Kokoro and Chimney!
شكرًا على المساعدة يا كوكورو-سان و تشيمني
Be careful!
توخّوا الحذر
Watch out for the government people!
احذروا من أتباع البحريّة
Yahoo! Let's go!
مرحى، هيّا بنا إلى مدينة اللّحم
Were you even listening?
هل كنت تنصت حتّى؟
Mmm. What a nice breeze!
يا لها من رياح لطيفة
Maybe we'll reach the City of Water sooner than expected.
قد نستطيع الوصول إلى مدينة الماء أسرع من المتوقّع
I hope so.
آمل ذلك
Luffy, leave scouting out the shipwright to me. I'll find us an incredibly gorgeous woman.
،يا لوفي دع مهمّة البحث عن سفان لي سأجد امرأةً فاتنة الجمال
Don't be dumb! We need a shipwright!
هل أنت غبيّ؟ إنّنا نتحدّث عن سفان
It's gotta be a big guy the size of a mountain! Five meters tall!
عليه أن يكون رجلًا ضخمًا كالجبل بطول خمسة أمتار
But if he's too big, he might not fit on this ship.
لكن إن كان ضخمًا جدًّا، لا ندري إن كان سيرتاح على هذه السّفينة
All that matters is that he's skilled, right?
المهمّ هو أن يكون ماهرًا، صحيح؟
The real question is if there's someone crazy enough to want to be on a pirate ship.
والمسألة الأهمّ هي ما إن كنّا سنجد أحدًا
I can't wait! We're gonna make a new friend!
أتطلّع إلى ذلك، سنرحّب بصديق جديد
We were lucky to stop at the station first since they drew a map for us.
حالفنا الحظّ للتّوقّف في المحطّة أوّلًا، بما أنّهم رسموا خريطة من أجلنا
If we go to the place on the map and find that Iceburg guy...
إن ذهبنا إلى المكان المُشار إليه ...في الخريطة وزرنا المدعو أيسبرغ
Oh, okay.
...فهمت
This tells me nothing!
بسيطة جدًّا على أن تُفهم
Whoa! This is like Luffy's art.
عجبًا، هذا أشبه برسم لوفي
Here. We need to keep an eye out for a guy like this.
إذًا سنبحث جميعًا عن شخص كهذا
I'd run if I saw a guy like that.
إن صادفت شخصًا مثله، سأهرب
Same here. I'd hop on the next ship and hightail it out to sea.
نعم، وأنا أيضًا، إن كان لي قارب فسأهرب إلى البحر
But a thug like this might chase me into open water like an octopus.
لكن يبدو أنّ لهذا الشّخص علاقة بالأخطبوطات
What are you guys jabbering about?
ما الّذي تثرثران به؟
Come here, guys!
حسنًا يا رفاق، تعالوا إلى هنا
I'll give you an allowance for the week we're ashore.
سأعطيكم مصروفًا من أجل الأسبوع الّذي سنبقى فيه هناك
Seriously?! Yay! I'm first!
حقًّا؟ مرحى، أنا أوّلًا
Whoa! That's generous!
هذا سخيّ
Hey! Get in line!
أنتم، قفوا في الصّفّ
You doing okay, Usopp?
ما الخطب يا أوسوبّ؟
This tinplate patchwork brings back memories of battles and adventure.
هذا التّرقيع الصّفيحيّ يعيد لي ذكريات معارك ومغامرات
I can't help but gush over the thought of her upcoming repairs.
تغمرني مشاعر عميقة عندما أفكّر .نّها ستُصلح عمّا قريب
I get it, but...
...فهمت ذلك، لكن
Huh?
أثّرت رحلتنا بشكلٍ كبير على الميري ولا سيّما بعد دخولنا إلى الغراند لاين
The deck creaks, and the ship's bottom is pretty leaky.
يصدر سطح السّفينة صريرًا كما أنّ التّسرّب في أسفل السّفينة سيّئ أيضًا
If nothing's done, that'll be it for both the ship and us.
إلّم نفعل شيئًا، فسنكون نحن وسفينتنا في خطر
Yeah, but we're filthy rich now.
نعم، لكنّنا نملك أموالًا طائلة الآن
We can make her good as new! And more powerful, too!
بإمكاننا أن نصلحها على أتمّ وجه كما يمكننا تعزيزها أيضًا
Yeah! More cannons!
حسنًا، لنحصل على المزيد من المدافع
Also, a bronze statue!
إذًا لنحصل على تمثال سفينة برونزيّ أيضًا
Hey, is that it?
لحظة، أليست تلك المنشودة؟
It's the island! We can see the island!
الجزيرة، أصبحت الجزيرة على مرآنا
Okay, guys! Row!
حسنًا يا رفاق، جدّفوا
We've got a decent tailwind. We shouldn't waste energy!
الرّياح كافية، لا تجعلنا نهدر طاقتنا
How wonderful!
...كم هي عجيبة
It's incredible!
...مذهلة
What is this place?!
ما هذا؟
The fountain's enormous!
يا لها من نافورة ضخمة
Unbelievable! An actual industrial city!
مذهلة، إنّها مدينة صناعيّة بحقّ
That's why it has the sea train.
لا عجب أن يملك هذا المكان قطارًا بحريًّا
That must be the station in front.
لا بدّ أنّ تلك في المقدّمة هي المحطّة
It says "Blue Station."
مكتوب عليها المحطّة الزّرقاء
I wonder where we dock.
أتساءل أين هو المرسى
In town somewhere?
لا بدّ أنّه في البلدة
Hey, you there!
يا رفاق
Pirates shouldn't openly sail out in front.
ليس من الجيّد أن يبحر القراصنة علانيّة في الأمام
Go around to the Backstreets!
التفّوا من حول الشّوارع الخلفيّة هناك
Okay! Thanks!
حسنًا، شكرًا
Whoa, this is amazing! A city on the water?!
عجبًا، هذا مذهل، مدينة في الماء؟
Wow! This place is cool! Such a pretty city!
،مذهل، هذا المكان رائع !يا لها من مدينة جميلة
But the city is flooded. The houses are submerged in the sea.
لكنّ المدينة غارقة والبيوت مغمورة في البحر
Look again.
ليس كذلك، صُمّمت المدينة لتكون قاعدتها غارقة
You can see the foundation underneath.
انظر للأساس الموجود أسفل المباني
Oh, true! The pillars raise the structures!
أنت محقّة، بُنيت الأعمدة لتكون أطول
I see... That's why it's called the City of Water, huh?
فهمت... لهذا تُدعى مدينة الماء إذًا؟
Hey, hurry up and dock the ship!
هيّا، أسرعوا وأرسوا السّفينة
Hey, listen up, you guys! Pirate ships should steer clear of this area!
يا رفاق، لا يجب على سفن القراصنة أن تأتي إلى هنا
Did you come here to plunder?
لِمَ أتيتم إلى هنا؟ لتنهبوا؟
No! We wanna get our ship repaired!
لا، نريد إصلاح سفينتنا
People just up and ask if we're gonna plunder...?
هل يسأل النّاس عادةً إن كنّا أتينا لنهبهم؟
In that case, there's a cape just ahead, so anchor your ship there for now!
إذًا ثمّة رأس في المقدّمة، لذا اُرسوا سفينتكم هناك حاليًّا
Okay!
عُلم
Thanks!
شكرًا
Again?
ثانيةً؟
What'd you expect? We're pirates, after all.
ما باليد حيلة، صحيح؟ نحن قراصنة في الأخير
This spot's okay, right?
يجدر أن تكون هذه المنطقة بخير، أليس كذلك؟
It sure is bleak though.
على أيّ حال، إنّه مكان مملّ
All right, then! Furl the sail!
حسنًا إذًا، اجمعوا الأشرعة
What're you doing?!
ما الّذي تفعله؟
Nothing! All I did was pull the rope!
لا شيء، سحبت الحبل فقط
You're kidding me! The Going Merry has gotten this rickety?
يا للهول، هل أصبحت الغوينغ ميري متهالكة بهذا القدر؟
Anyway, why aren't the people on this island scared of pirates?
بالمناسبة، لِمَ لا يخاف أهل هذه الجزيرة من القراصنة؟
Pirates probably come here for ships too.
ربما لأن القراصنة يعدون من زبائن حوضهم للسفانة
Less talking! More fixing!
كفاك لغوًا وأصلحها بسرعة
Maybe they have sentries strong enough to deal with pirates who cause a ruckus?
ربّما لأنّهم يملكون حرّاسًا شخصيّين أقوياء كفايةً ليتعاملوا مع القراصنة الّذين يفتعلون الجلبة؟
They probably do, considering the size of the city.
...ذلك ما في الأمر غالبًا باعتبار حجم هذه المدينة
Is that so?! Then what're we gonna do? This is bad.
حقًّا؟ ماذا سنفعل إذًا؟ هذا سيّئ
Why would it be bad? We're customers.
لِمَ قد يكون سيّئًا؟ نحن زبائن
Y-You think so?
أ-أهذا رأيك؟
Okay, then! See you later!
حسنًا إذًا، أراكم لاحقًا
Wait, Luffy and Usopp!
انتظرا يا لوفي و أوسوبّ
You two, come with me.
ستأتيان أنتما معي
Come with you where?
إلى أين؟
First, we'll take Miss Kokoro's letter of introduction and go find the man named Iceburg.
أوّلًا، سنأخذ الرّسالة المرجعيّة الّتي أعطتنا إيّاها كوكورو-سان
We'll ask him to facilitate the ship's repair.
وسنطلب منه أن يساعدنا على تدبير أمر إصلاح السّفينة
Then we have to find a place where we can cash in our gold.
كما يجب أن نجد مكانًا حيث نستطيع تصريف ذهبنا إلى مال
If that's it, then okay! Onward! To the City of Water!
فهمت... حسنًا إذًا، على أيّ حال لنذهب إلى مدينة الماء
You're forgetting the gold.
نسيت الذّهب
Hey! Some pirates are raising hell at Dock One!
اسمعوا، بدأ بعض القراصنة بافتعال الجلبة في الحوض الأول
What?! For real?!
ماذا؟ أهذا صحيح؟
We'd better hurry and see!
من الأفضل أن نذهب إلى هناك حالًا
I don't understand what you're talking about.
لا أعي ما تقول
Well, actually...
...في الواقع
I thought about it carefully.
فكّرتُ في الأمر مليًّا
I thought about it really carefully.
بل فكّرتُ فيه على مهل
While it's true that you guys repaired our ship,
صحيحٌ أنّكم أصلحتم سفينتنا
I couldn't help but notice the invoice was a bit too high.
لكن كيفما نظرت إلى الأمر فكّرتُ أنّ الرّسوم مرتفعة للغاية
You're interrupting our work.
أنتم تعرقلون عملنا
So... I decided not to pay—not one belly.
لذا قرّرت... ألّا أدفع ولا بيري واحد
Thanks for the flawless repairs!
شكرًا على الإصلاحات الممتازة
Plus, it's all free!
وفوق ذلك بالمجّان
Well, Kalifa, what's going on over there?
حسنًا يا كاليفا، ما الّذي يجري هناك؟
You see, Mr. Iceburg, they're customers of Dock One.
نعم يا أيسبرغ-سان. إنّهم زبائن الحوض الأول
The repairs are complete, but they refuse to pay.
بعد انتهاء العمل، يقولون أنّهم لن يدفعوا
That's sexual harassment.
إنّه تحرّش جنسيّ
Well... I suppose that is sexual harassment.
حسنًا... إنّه تحرّش جنسيّ
B-Boss!
ز-زعيم
– Boss!
زعيم
Oh, pardon me.
آسف
You son of a bitch! You should watch where you're going!
أيّها الحقير، راقب جيّدًا أين تذهب
Y-You bastards! Are you picking a fight?! Just who do you think we are?!
أ-أيّها الأوغاد، هل تريدون القتال؟ من تحسبوننا؟
Hey, have you test-fired the cannon?
أخبرني، هل اختبرت إطلاق المدافع؟
Oh, not yet, sir.
ليس بعد يا سيّدي
Dammit! Who the hell are you guys?!
سحقًا، من أنتم بالضّبط؟
We'll remember this!
لن ننسى هذا
The pirate way of doing things
شركة غاليلا منطقة صناعة السفن بووتر سيفن (مزود خاص لحكومة العالم)
Should we go to the exchange shop first?
لِمَ لا نذهب لمحلّ تصريف المال أوّلًا؟
Why? Let's go to the shipyard.
لماذا؟ لنذهب إلى حوض السفانة
But we can't just walk around the island with this much gold. It puts me on edge.
لكن لا يمكننا أن نجول الجزيرة حاملين هذا الكمّ من الذّهب فذلك يصيبني بالتوتر
Isn't it worth the same after it's exchanged?
تظلّ قيمته نفسها وإن صرّفناه إلى مال
Even so, the size of our load might attract attention, don't you think?
صحيح، لكنّ هذه الكومة الكبيرة ستجذب انتباه النّاس، أليس كذلك؟
What if we run into no good thieves?
ماذا إن صادفنا لصوصًا أشرار؟
But we're thieves too!
نحن اللّصوص
He's got a point. Trading it in for bills would mean we each hold on to some of it.
معه حقّ، إن صرّفناه إلى أموالٍ يمكننا حملها جميعًا
Hey, what's with that remark?
لم ترق لي طريقة كلامك
Is there a problem if I'm the one carrying it?
بدا وكأنّ حملي إيّاه هو المشكلة
Yeah. You might drop it or lose it somewhere.
نعم، قد تسقطه في مكانٍ ما أو تفقده
Yeah, he would. It's Luffy after all.
نعم، سيفعل، نحن نتحدّث عن لوفي
What?! Guys! Don't you trust me?!
ماذا؟ أنتما، ألا تثقان بي؟
– Nope!
نعم
Is this the only entrance to the city?
أهذا المدخل الوحيد للمدينة؟
A rental bull shop?
متجر تأجير بُول؟
What's that?
ما معنى ذلك؟
What do they rent out?
ما الّذي يؤجّرونه؟
What's a "bull"?
ما معنى "بُول"؟
Beats me. Bulldogs?
لا أدري، ربّما بولدغ؟
Can't be, right?
هذا مستبعد، صحيح؟
Excuse me! We'd like to rent some bulls!
المعذرة، نريد تأجير بعض البُول
Ask what they are first!
اسأل عن معناها أوّلًا
Welcome! Here to rent bulls, right? For how many?
مرحبًا، تريدون تأجير البُول، صحيح؟ كم عددكم؟
Three of us!
ثلاثة
What kind of bulls would you like?
أيّ نوع من البُول تريدون؟
There are three classes: yagara, rabuka, and king.
"ثمّة ثلاثة أصناف: "ياغارا" و"رابوكا" و"كينغ
Well, for the three of you, two yagaras would probably do.
بالنّسبة لكم أنتم الثّلاثة اثنان من صنف ياغارا سيكفيان
Okay, roast 'em nice and tasty!
حسنًا، أرجو أن تحمّرهما بشكلٍ جميل ولذيذ
Don't say weird things, you weirdo!
غريبة، هذه المحادثة غريبة
Oh? Your log pose led you here?
هكذا إذًا؟ تبعتم البوصلة المسجّلة إلى هنا؟
Yep.
أجل - هذا إنجاز كبير منكم -
Then you had no idea what bulls were, did you?
لم تكونوا تعرفون ما معنى بُول، أليس كذلك؟
– Right.
صحيح - حسنًا، باختصار، هذه هي بُول -
Yagara bulls. You'll see them all over town.
إنّها بُول من صنف ياغارا وهي سائدة في كلّ البلدة
In this area, there's a fish called a yagara that swims with its head out.
توجد في هذه المنطقة سمكة تدعى ياغارا وهي تسبح ورأسها خارج عن سطح الماء
This is the City of Water. There are more canals than walkways.
هذه مدينة الماء، ثمّة قنوات أكثر من الممرّات
The residents here see bulls as a necessary form of transportation.
لذا فإنّ البُول وسيلة نقل ضروريّة من أجل سكّان المدينة
Same goes for any sightseeing on the island.
الأمر سيان عندما تذهبون للسّياحة في هذه الجزيرة
That fish is pulling a boat?
تسحب السّمكة القارب؟
Actually, they let people ride on their backs.
بل تدع النّاس تركب على ظهرها بالأحرى
Well, it's like horseback riding or riding in a carriage on land.
الأمر أشبه بامتطاء الخيل أو ركوب ...عربة على اليابسة
In we go!
حسنًا
You see the fish pen there? Well, try and ride on one. It's comfortable.
أترون حظيرة السّمك هناك؟ جرّبوا ركوبها فذلك مريح
For a couple of two-passenger yagara bulls, it'll be 2,000 belly, all told.
ستكلّفكم 2000 بيري لاثنين بُول لراكبَين من صنف ياغارا
Wow, they're cute!
عجبًا، إنّها ظريفة
It's a fish that looks like a horse.
إنّها سمكة تشبه الحصان
You jerk! What'd you do that for?!
أيّها النّذل، لِمَ فعلت ذلك؟
Oh? He must like you. Let's get that one for you.
لا بدّ أنّه استلطفك، لنجهّزه من أجلك
Can he carry heavy stuff okay?
أيمكنه حمل الأغراض الثّقيلة؟
Their power is incredible! They're often used when moving household goods.
قوّتها مذهلة، حتّى أنّ بإمكانك استخدامها للتّرحال
Quite the bag, huh? Whatcha got in there?
تلك الحقيبة إذًا؟ ماذا يوجد بداخلها؟
Gold.
ذهب
Good one! Whatever it is, they can handle it.
أنت مضحك، أيًّا كان، ليس هناك مشكلة
See?
أرأيت؟
Whoa! Gimme!
عجبًا، أعطني القليل
No way!
مستحيل
This guy's awfully honest.
...يا له من عجوز صريح
And you! Don't show it off to others so casually!
وأنت، لا تُرِه للآخرين بهذه البساطة
Why's that? It's no big deal.
لماذا؟ لن يضرّ ذلك، صحيح؟
My... That was a surprise.
...يا إلهي... يا لها من مفاجأة
Well, then... It'll be a million belly for two yagara bulls.
حسنًا... سأحاسبكم مليونيّ بيري لِقاء اثنين من البُول من صنف ياغارا
Hey, the price went up, pops.
لقد رفعت الثّمن أيّها العمّ
Oh, right, are there any exchange shops around here?
بالمناسبة، أثمّة أيّ محلّات صرف في الجوار؟
Yeah, there are, but with that amount of gold, the shops here probably won't have enough money.
أجل، هنالك، لكن مع تلك الكميّة من الذّهب
You should go downtown on Shipyard Island.
عليكم الذّهاب إلى وسط المدينة في جزيرة السفانة
Downtown Shipyard Island? Where's that?
وسط المدينة في جزيرة السفانة؟ أين تقع؟
In that direction. Take this with you.
هنالك، خذوا هذه معكم
A map?! Aha!
خريطة؟
This'll be helpful! Thanks!
ستكون مفيدة، شكرًا
Pops, is the shipyard that way, too?
يا عمّ، هل حوض السفانة هناك أيضًا؟
Yeah. The world's number one shipyard!
نعم، الحوض الأوّل في العالم
Perfect! Once we get the money, we'll be real close to the shipyard.
هذا ممتاز، فور أن نحصل على المال بإمكاننا الذّهاب إليه على الفور
Yeah. We can finally have the Going Merry repaired!
نعم، بوسعنا إصلاح الغوينغ ميري أخيرًا
And we'll find a shipwright, too! I'm getting excited!
وسنجد سفان أيضًا، بدأتُ أتحمّس
Well, then...
...حسنًا - هل نذهب؟ -
Alright! Go, yagara!
حسنًا، هيّا بنا يا ياغارا
Thanks for your business! Be careful!
سرّني العمل معكم، توخّوا الحذر
Full speed to the shipyard!
أسرع إلى حوض السفانة
Yahoo!
مرحى